Email: enunes1@asu.edu **ERIC NUNES**

1215 E. Lemon Street, Apt #105, Tempe, AZ-85281

Website: https://efnunes.github.io/

SUMMARY

Computer Engineering Graduate student with 3 years' experience in research and development of data analysis tools. Hands-on experience with Python, R, SQL, C++, and MATLAB. Knowledgeable in processes and tools related to Big Data and Data Science.

EDUCATION

PhD in Computer Engineering **Present**

GPA: 4.0 Arizona State University, AZ

Master of Science in Electrical Engineering May, 2012

Syracuse University, NY

Bachelor of Science in Electronics and Telecommunication

June, 2010

University of Mumbai, India

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Machine Learning: Classification, regression, clustering, anomaly detection, feature engineering, online learning, Experience with deep learning.

- **Programming Languages**: Python, MATLAB, C++, Prolog, HTML, LaTeX. Familiar with C, PHP, LISP, R.
- Libraries: scikit-learn, Weka, Pandas, OpenCV, Theano, Caffe.
- Databases: SQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB.
- Big Data and Cloud: Splunk, Spark, Familiar with Big Data Processing Platforms: Hadoop and Cloud tools: Amazon S3.

KEY PROFESSIONAL AND RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Security Automation Intern (Data Science), PayPal

Tools: Python, Splunk, Spark.

May 2017- August 2017

Contact: 315-439-3089

- Analyzed user login activity using Akamai logs and enriched it with other data feeds such as threat intelligence, merchant data, credential dumps.
- Implemented operational Anomaly detection models to detect Account Takeover (ATO) attacks to raise alerts for automated mitigation.
- Visualized ATO attacks in real time on a dashboard in Splunk to aid risk to flag fraudulent transactions.

Data Scientist, Cyber Reconnaissance Inc. (CYR3CON)

August 2016 - April 2017

Tools: Python, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Spark.

- Designed a system to store and mine data from darknet markets and forums.
- Implemented learning models to classify data related to malicious hacking (from products on markets and topics on forums).
- Built learning models for predicting likelihood of exploitation of a vulnerability, named-entity recognition using RNN/LSTM seq2seq models, identification of malicious web pages.

Research Consultant, CYR3CON (Client: SiteLock)

June 2016 - August 2016

Tools: Python.

- Analyzed large dataset of malicious web scripts (PHP/HTML) to generate features indicative of malicious activity.
- Developed classification models to classify web scripts as malicious or not using the generated features in Python.
- Achieved malicious script detection rate of >90%.

Graduate Research Assistant, CySIS Lab, Arizona State University

August 2014 - Present

Tools: Python, PostgreSQL, Prolog, tcpflow.

- Modeling of threat actors: Identifying cyber adversaries using argumentation and machine learning models (knowledge base: 10 million attacks).
- Proactive Cyber-Threat Intelligence: Built a system to crawl and parse the Darknet (markets and forums) to extract cyber threat intelligence including zero-day exploits using data mining and machine learning techniques. Identifying targeted software through disclosed vulnerabilities on Darknet.
- Malware task identification: Identifying the tasks that a piece of malware was designed to perform on the system (adversarial intent) using cognitive learning models.

PATENTS

- Systems and Methods for Data Driven Malware Task Identification. Submitted, 2016. **Provisional: 62/182,006**.
- Intelligent darkweb crawling infrastructure for cyber threat intelligence collection. Licensed to CYR3CON. Provisional: 62/409,291. Technology featured in Forbes, MIT Tech Review, ACM TechNews, Cisco Continuum.

REFERRED PUBLICATIONS

https://efnunes.github.io/publication.html